ALEXANDRA EESLEY

Full Stack Developer & Digital Marketing Expert

Email: alexandra.eeslev@gmail.com

Cell: 763.226.9665

Portfolio: aeeslev.github.io/alexandra-eeslev-portfolio/

Github: aithub.com/aeeslev

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/alexandra-eeslev-0998a81a/

SUMMARY

Full stack web developer and digital marketing expert with extensive entrepreneurship and leadership experience. Known for tackling problem solving with a fresh approach, using a unique ability to switch between data-driven strategy, and beautifully intentional design. Invigorated by fast-paced environments, challenges, teamwork, collaboration and continuous evolution through learning.

RECENT PROJECTS



SMUG SHEEP | A Community for Positivity

→ GitHub: https://aithub.com/ivocus/Smua-Sheep → Deployed: https://drv-oasis-44384.herokuapp.com/

Smug Sheep is a gratitude driven community where users can anonymously post and read positive news to help bolster their mental health throughout the Covid-19 pandemic. The application utilizes HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Node.JS, Auth0, Particles, Material-UI, MongoDB, Mongoose, Axios, Express, and Atlas. This project was created by a team of four contributors, and presented to a group of 30 developers in a Demo Day simulation.



■ VEGGIE VISION | Understand Your Food

→ GitHub: https://github.com/aeeslev/veggie-vision → Deployed: https://drv-oasis-44384.herokuapp.com/

Veguru is a user-friendly application that helps users live a healthier lifestyle by providing them with key information about a variety of vegetables. The application utilizes HTML, CSS, JQuery, MySQL, Foundations, Handlebars, and Express. This project was created by a team of four contributors, and presented to industry professionals at a live Demo Day event.



RESTAURANT ROULETTE | Dynamic Restaurant Generator

→ **GitHub:** https://github.com/k1te-m/Project-1-Restaurant-Roulette

→ Deployed: https://k1te-m.github.io/Project-1-Restaurant-Roulette/

Restaurant Roulette is a dynamic application that helps users decide where to eat based on their search location and the current weather conditions for that location. The application utilizes HTML, CSS, JQuery, & Foundations, and pulls in API data from the Open Weather API and Zomato API's. This project was created by a team of two contributors, and presented to a group of 30 developers in a Demo Day simulation.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Development

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, MySQL, NOSQL, Express, React, MongoDB, Mongoose, Axios, Atlas, Handlebars, Heroku, Bootstrap, Foundations, Material-UI, Github, VS Code, Wordpress

Marketing

Google Ads, Google Analytics, Moz, SEMrush, Youtube, Mailchimp, Constant Contact, Hubspot, SproutSocial, Hootsuite, Buffer, Canva, Adobe Creative Suite, all social platforms.

Professional

Slack, Salesforce, Trello, Basecamp, Asana, Quickbooks, Google Suite.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

OWNER & MARKETING CONSULTANT | EESLEY CONSULTING

February 2016 – Present

- → Built a solopreneur consultancy from scratch to six figures in 3 years, with an average 43% growth YOY.
- → Empowered 20+ businesses to complete strategic marketing initiatives to boost growth and catalyze impact.
- → Built highly specialized knowledge of Google products to deliver outstanding SEO results and growth for clients.
- → Continuously pushed individual growth through learning initiatives, conferences, courses, and networking.
- → Managed all aspects of running a small business, from analytics to client communication, to finished deliverables.

DIRECTOR OF MARKETING & SALES | URBAN LEASH

October 2015 – February 2016

- → Increased lead generation and conversion rates by optimizing partnership, digital and grassroots channels.
- → Managed all content generation including website, social media, email campaigns and partnership collateral.
- → Hired and managed a team of Brand Ambassadors to increase lead generation and overall brand exposure.
- → Developed structures, best practices and reporting for lead optimization and channel growth analysis.
- → Analyzed customer trends to discover opportunities for growth, upselling and improved customer retention.

DIRECTOR OF MARKETING | INTEGRATED DATA STORAGE (IDS)

October 2014 - October 2015

- → Executed a complete rebrand, including web design, content creation, collateral and creative vision.
- → Managed all content creation: website, case studies, PowerPoint presentations, press releases and blogs.
- → Designed comprehensive marketing campaigns, boosting customer engagement and generating sales leads.
- → Managed external vendor relationships and utilized funds to plan events boosting client engagement and leads.
- → Contributed strategic insights as leadership team member, evaluating performance metrics to drive decisions.

MARKETING MANAGER | WILLIS GROUP

August 2013 – October 2014

MARKETING COORDINATOR

January 2012 - August 2013

- → Created content for and designed all promotional, educational, recruiting communications and blog.
- → Designed various microsites promoting affiliate agent membership programs, directly increasing membership
- → Worked with the IT Team to re-design the outward aesthetic and internal functionality of the company website.
- → Researched and implemented the Salesforce CRM for a new client development department.

EDUCATION

NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY | Full Stack Development Certificate

2020

DEPAUL UNIVERSITY | MBA in Leadership & Change

2016

UNIVERSITY OF WISCONSIN | BA in Strategic Communications & Double Major in Spanish

2011

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Project Frontline Covid-19 Support Campaign | Founding Team Member
2020

Break the Silence Community Education Event | Founder
2018

True Mentors Leadership Forum

Summer

2018